writerbay.com 2019-02-01

# WriterBay.com - Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy ("Policy", "Privacy Policy") along with our Terms and Conditions is part of our agreement with you. This Policy describes our privacy practices and explains when and how we collect your information, including your personal data, how we use such information, and the circumstances under which we may disclose such information to third parties. This Privacy Policy shall be applied to all the services rendered by WriterBay.com.

Company is a "controller" of your personal data, i.e. the person responsible for information you provide through this Website and/or using our services. According to Processing of Personal Data (Protection of Individuals) Law 2001 and General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 ("GDPR") "controller" is a person that determines the purposes and the means of processing of your personal data.

We take your privacy very seriously and you can be sure that we will process your personal data fairly, lawfully and transparently. Therefore, we encourage you to review this Policy very carefully and with due attention as it describes the personal data we are collecting about you, how it is used, our principles and practices related to processing your personal data.

This Privacy Policy shall be applied to all the services rendered by the Company.

## Our Policy Towards Children

Our services and our Website are not directed to children under the age of fourteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of fourteen. If you are under fourteen years of age, you are not required to, and please do not provide us with any personal information through our Website and/or services. If we become aware that we have inadvertently collected or received personal data from a child under the age of fourteen without parental consent, we will delete this data from our records. If you might have any data from or/and about a child under the age of fourteen, please contact us via [support@writerbay.com](mailto:support@writerbay.com)

## What Personal Data We Collect

Processing of your personal data is lawful only if it is permitted under EU data protection law. In other words, your personal data may be collected and/or processed only if we have a certain legal basis to do so. Legal basis is the foundation for your personal data processing. The law requires us to have a lawful basis for each and every instance of data processing of your personal data and we treat this requirement very seriously.

**Information you provide to us when filling out the registration form.**

If you decide to become our freelance writer, you have to fill in the online registration form and provide all the necessary data, including your name, email, phone number, payment information, educational certificates, gender and country of residence. We will use your email to send you information considering orders you work on and other organizational issues. We have to hold the personal details of the people who have decided to join our team in order to communicate with them.

_Purpose_. We require this information to (a) grant you the access to our program for freelance writers, including to verify your identity and maintain a record of your transactions and interactions with us; (b) to be able to contact you if necessary and to define what types of papers are more suitable for you to be able to meet requirements of our customers and deliver the best quality papers to them. This is the information which we receive directly from you.

_Legal Basis_. Our legal basis for such processing is the performance of a contract between you and the Company and/or taking steps at your request to enter into such a contract. We also may use your contact details based on our legitimate interests to reply to communications you sent to us.

This information will be used only by our customer care agents and will on no condition be disclosed to any third party; it is never sold, rented or shared.

All the personal details of writers are not disclosed to any third parties in the process of their transfer to us, which is guaranteed by our use of SSL-certificate.

**Information you provide to us when working with your account control panel.**

As soon as you fill out the registration form, you are forwarded to your personal control panel. In there you will have to download the necessary papers and pass tests for knowledge of the English language. Test results are visible only to our Support members and are not disclosed to any third parties. 

To be able to work on the orders, writers also have to provide their payment details. This information is used only to process payments on payment days and is visible only to our support members. Confidentiality is additionally secured by SSL-certificate that we have, which guarantees that in the process of data transfer to us it won’t become known to any third parties. This information is used only by our customer care agents and is on no condition sold, rented or shared.

_Purpose_. We require this information to assess you as a freelance writer to grant you an access to our freelance writers' program. This is the information which we receive directly from you.

_Legal Basis_. Our legal basis for such processing is the performance of a contract between you and the Company and/or taking steps at your request to enter into such a contract.

**Online Activity Information and Information about Your Use of Our Website**

With regard to each of your visits to our Website, we will collect your IP address, your operating system, your browser ID, website that refers you to us; pages you have viewed on our Website; country of your location.

_Purpose_. This information is used by us for fraud and abuse detection; to ensure the security of our Website; to enable administration of our Website; to analyze your use of our Website; and to deliver relevant Website content, information and advertisements to you and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising.

_Legal Basis_. Our legal basis for this collecting and processing of your personal data is either your consent or our legitimate interests to enable us to properly administer our Website and our business and to grow our business and to decide our marketing strategy.

**Information for Marketing Activities**

Our legal basis for processing of your personal data to send you marketing communications is either your consent or our legitimate interests (namely to grow and develop our business).

Nonetheless, please note that we will never share your personal data with any third party for their own marketing purposes without your prior express consent.

YOU HAVE THE RIGHT AT ANY TIME TO ASK US TO STOP PROCESSING YOUR DATA FOR DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES by sending an email to [support@writerbay.com](mailto:support@writerbay.com) or by following the unsubscribe links on any marketing message we sent to you.

## Your Consent

If we are processing your personal data on the basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time by emailing us at: support@writerbay.com. Such withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of our processing prior to the withdrawal of consent.

## Data Sharing and Categories of Recipients of Your Personal Data

We may share your personal data and nonpersonally identifiable information with:

_Our Affiliates_ : we may cooperate with other businesses or companies (partners) for delivering better services and a stable growth of the Company. In some occasions, they need your personal data to deliver their services and enable various transactions.

_Third-party service providers_ : We may employ other companies to perform as our intermediate parties, including:

  * providers we engage to host our Website;
  * payment service providers;
  * providers we engage to send emails on our behalf;
  * analytics and search engine providers that we engage to improve and optimize our Website and Services;
  * affiliate network through which you have accessed our Website.

As a result, we may share your personal data (both non-personal and personally-identifiable) with them. These service providers will use this information solely to assist us.

_Third parties in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale etc_. We may sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business and/or our assets to (with) third parties. We may also decide to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If latter happens, then the new owners may use your personal data but, in any case, in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy.

_Third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation_ : We may disclose your personal data if it is required by legal processes, litigation, law, or governmental or public institutions or authorities. We may also disclose information about you if it is necessary for purpose of law enforcement, national security, or protection of our users and/or operations.

_Our professional advisers who provide us with consultancy, banking, legal and accounting services._

## How Long We Store Your Data

We will store your personal data for as long as you have an account with us. After your account is terminated (for whatever reason), we will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes determined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer period is required or permitted by law.

## International Transfers

We may transfer the personal data we gather about you with to third parties located in countries other than the one you are located for the purposes for which they have been collected. This also includes countries which are not regarded as part of the European Economic Area (EEA) and which may not offer the same safeguards to personal data protection as within the EEA.

Any such transfer will only occur in cases where, at least:

The third-party recipient is located in a country which, according to the European Commission, provides an adequate level of protection for your personal information; and/or

under an agreement which satisfies EU requirements for the transfer of personal data to data processors or data controllers outside the EEA, such as standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission.

## Complaints

If you have any concerns about how we collect or process your data you have the right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority, which is Office of the Commissioner for Personal Data Protection:

1 Iasonos str., 1082 Nicosia  
P.O.Box 23378, 1682 Nicosia  
Tel: +357 22818456  
Fax: +357 22304565  
Email: commissioner@dataprotection.gov.cy

## How We Protect Your Personal Information

We have provided reasonable security measures to protect your personal data that is maintained on our servers from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, which include encryption on processed data, limited and password-protected access, high security public/private keys, and SSL encryption to protect transmission of data.

However, please note that no security system is impassable and unfortunately it may be possible for third parties to access or intercept information that you provide us with in spite of these measures. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of your information and cannot be held liable for unauthorized access to your information.

**Cookies.**

When visiting WriterBay.com, we send one or several cookies to your computer, which is required by the Google Analytics system that we use to develop our site. Cookies are files that allow us to define the type of visitor’s browser. These files may also track visitor’s preferences as well as some additional data. 

If you don’t want to make this data known to us and all the other sites, you can disallow your browser to receive cookies. However, bear in mind, some sites will not properly function without Cookies, and WriterBay.com belongs to them. We make use of these files to find out how our visitors use our website and draw up statistical reports to develop our service and make it suitable for all the Writers and visitors. For additional information considering cookies – view www.aboutcookies.org/, to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics resort to http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

In case we use the abovementioned data in a way which is different from the purpose why it was collected, we will ask for your prior consent.

On no condition will the data collected for the above described aims be disclosed to any third party. 

## Contact Details. Complaints and suggestions

To maintain the highest level of quality, we are always open to our Writers’ and visitors’ comments and requests. You can notify us if you consider that our collection or application of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate. We are also waiting for any suggestions considering improvement of our service. You can always contact us via email support@writerbay.com.

## Your Rights

In accordance with EU data protection laws, you have the right to access and rectify your personal data, in order to rectify, complete, update, or delete your data that is inaccurate, incomplete, or outdated, or whose collection, use, communication, or storage is prohibited.

You also have the right to request the limitation of the processing, and to oppose on legal basis the processing of your personal data.

Where applicable, you may request the portability of your personal data or, where the legal basis for the processing is consent, withdraw their consent at any time.

All requests for such data should be sent via our email: support@writerbay.com

## Links disclaimer

WriterBay.com may include links to other sites at its pages, which on no condition presupposes validation of these sites’ content. The moment you leave WriterBay.com through link or in any other way, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that site, including but not limited to its Privacy Policy.

## Amendments to this Privacy Policy

We strive to improve the quality of our service and thus can change this Privacy Policy from time to time. All the amendments will be available for view at this page. This Privacy Policy was last updated on June 1st, 2018.
